POOJA PATEL

Data Science Enthusiast | Software Developer | Graphic Designer

Po: Vasai, Ta:Dabhoi, Dist: Vadodara in www.linkedin.com/in/pooja-patel-6b9224145/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMURY

An ambitious student and Software developer with proper training and experience in Java and its frameworks programming. Knowledgeable in wide range of development programming languages and methodologies. Bright critical thinker with proven talent for learning quickly in result-oriented environment. Aiming to gain more experience in the field of computer Science and Engineering.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering

ITM Vocational University, Vadodara, 2016-2020

- Completed four-year bachelor's course with 9.14 CGPA

Higher Secondary School

Atmiya Institute, Bharuch, 2014-2016

-Achieved a score of 60% in 12th Grade.

EXPERIENCE

Intern as a Software Developer

Primavera Systems, vadodara | Dec,2019 - July, 2020

- Documented all software development methodologies in technical manuals to be used by developers in future projects.
- Designed intuitive user interface using knowledge of various front-end technologies. Moreover, designed database to remove complexity as well as improve user experience.
- Prepare test plans and test cases based on requirement documents for "Candidate Assessment System".

Freelancer Shutterstock Contributor

Shutterstock, New York, US | April,2019 - Present

- Used Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to develop product mockups and prototype designs
- Applied knowledge of production to create high-quality images.
- Developed creative design for marketing packages including print material, brochures, banners and signs.

Graphic Designer And Web Developer

Nexode Media | July,2019 - October,2019

- · Worked with clients to gather and define requirements, establish scopes and managing project milestones.
- Conceptualized and developed graphics products for "The Global Youth Leaders Model United Nations" project using Adobe Illustrator.

MAIN INTEREST

- Programming
- Visual Studio
- Spring Tool
- WordPress
- Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop
- MS Office(power-point, Excel(advanced), word)

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY

- HTML5,CSS3, Javascript,MYSQl, PHP, Bootstrap,XML,Hibernate,Spring Boot
- RDBMS,DBMS
- C(Proficient)
- C++(Proficient)
- Java(Proficient)
- Python(Intermediate)

REAL LIFE PROJECTS

Candidate Assessment System (Technology - Java, Jsp, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JPA)

- HR can set, track and have access to interviews with reminders, notifications and automated emails.
- Interviewer can provide feedback and share to HR through Candidate Assessment System.

Infinity Infographics (Technology - WordPress)

- User can download infographics by just clicking on download button and can use it in various ways for instance, in presentation, newspaper, books etc, to show data in an interesting way. .
- Not only this but user also can edit those downloaded files by using appropriate tools and can add their own data.

Worketeria - A work portal (Technology - HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap 4, PHP, MYSQL)

- A job portal where underprivileged workers those who do not have proper work and degree can get work by using this platform.
- This platform is also for them who do not have time to find workers for their work for instance, renovation, plumbing, etc.

BotFuel (Technology - ChatBot (AI))

- In India, the government is providing a plethora of Yojanas for poor people. However, in some circumstances, people do not get enough information regarding these YOJANAS and can get easily misguided. By using this chatbot, people do not have to go through all that hassle.
- User just need to speak or write about YOJNA of which they want information .After that, chatbot will provide all the important information about that particular YOJANA

ITMVU (Technology - HTML,CSS,PHP)

- This website was built to help students of ITM Vocational University, vadodara, Gujarat, India; to attend any miss lectures of any subjects.
- They can also receive an update of any new events, result and many more.

AWARDS AND ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS

- Secured 3rd rank in "Major League Hacking 2018" hackathon hosted by Github.
- Received Gold Medal in inter-college Badminton Competition.
- Secured 1st rank in TECHNOVISION Competition held by ITM Vocational University, vadodara.
- Awarded certificate for Volunteering in Maker Fest Vadodara in 2019.
- Executive Marketing of CSE Chapter at ITM Vocational University, vadodara.
- Internshala Student Partner 12.0 (2019).
- Awarded certificate for volunteering in International Women's Day.2018 held by Women Techmaker .

RESERACH AND PUBLICATIONS

 Co-authored and published research paper with the help of the professor SWATI SAXENA in journal of INTERNATIONAL JOURNAL OF RESEARCH AND ANALYTICAL REVIEWS (IJRAR).

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Certification of The Fundamental of Digital Marketing | Google | 2019.
- Certification of Indian Student Forum | IUCEE and SPEED | 2016.
- Certification of Regional Student Forum | IUCEE and SPEED | 2017.

LANGUAGES

- English
- Gujarati
- Hindi
- French(Beginner)

DECLARATION

I, hereby declare that all the details stated above are genuine and valid to the best of my knowledge.